export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The art of treating a dead body with drugs and chemicals to keep it from decaying by the Ancient Egyptians is termed",
A: "burying.",
B: "embalming",
C: "mummification",
D: "scarcophag us",
answer: "C. mummification",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Works of art are displaced and sold in a",
A: "Gallery",
B: "Mausoleum",
C: "Museum",
D: "Studio",
answer: "A. Gallery",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A mythological being with a lionâ€™s body, and a human head is termed",
A: "Androsphinx",
B: "Criosphinx",
C: "Hierocosphinx",
D: "Sphinx",
answer: "D. Sphinx",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Animism is the belief that inanimate objects have",
A: "Beauty",
B: "Children",
C: "Gold",
D: "Life",
answer: "D. Life",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. One reason for appreciation in visual arts is to",
A: "Appraise an artifact",
B: "Criticize an artifact",
C: "Decorate an artifact",
D: "Judge an artifact",
answer: "A. Appraise an artifact",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following options is an example of sculpture in the round?",
A: "Fresco",
B: "Mural",
C: "Plaque",
D: "Statue",
answer: "D. Statue",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The surface quality of an object is referred to as",
A: "Rough",
B: "Smooth",
C: "Tactile",
D: "Texture",
answer: "D. Texture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A process of making a design on wood or calabash with a hot metal tool is a",
A: "Pantograph",
B: "Pyrograph",
C: "Skiving",
D: "Tooling",
answer: "B. Pyrograph",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Huge statues that were carved and placed at the front of tombs were known as",
A: "catacombs",
B: "mummy",
C: "pharaohs",
D: "sphinx",
answer: "D. sphinx",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Most traditional arts were based on",
A: "aesthetics",
B: "beliefs",
C: "festivals",
D: "initiation",
answer: "B. beliefs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Traditional symbols are important because they",
A: "are easily carve",
B: "attract foreigners.",
C: "communicate ideas.",
D: "sell at high prices.",
answer: "C. communicate ideas",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The circular pillar in the middle of the traditional stool represents",
A: "female embrace.",
B: "male children.",
C: "presence of Go",
D: "support of the earth",
answer: "D. support of the earth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Many clans and families practice face-marking as a means of",
A: "identification.",
B: "keeping their custom.",
C: "representing ancestors.",
D: "spiritual upliftment.",
answer: "A. identification",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Letters that stand erect with ornamental projections and alternating thick and thin strokes are",
A: "freestyle letters.",
B: "gothic letters",
C: "italic letters",
D: "roman letters",
answer: "D. roman letters",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The process of polishing the surface of pots with a tool to make it smooth and shining is",
A: "batt",
B: "bisque",
C: "burnishing",
D: "saggars",
answer: "C. burnishing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A curved tool made of wood, metal or plastic used for shaping, scraping or smoothing clay objects is called",
A: "frog",
B: "raku",
C: "rib",
D: "spatula",
answer: "C. rib",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which types of colours are needed to create recession in painting?",
A: "Analogous colours",
B: "Cool colours",
C: "Primary colours",
D: "Warm colours",
answer: "B. Cool colours",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A narrow strip of hide or leather used in sewing leather works is",
A: "belt",
B: "lace",
C: "rope",
D: "thong",
answer: "D. thong",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Using rolled clay for modelling is known as",
A: "coiling",
B: "moulding",
C: "rolling",
D: "roping",
answer: "A. coiling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. In casting, you have to first prepare",
A: "Grog",
B: "Moulds",
C: "Sand bags",
D: "Weft",
answer: "B. Moulds",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is an artificial line?",
A: "Animal trails",
B: "Cracks on dried tree back",
C: "Roads",
D: "Vein of leaves",
answer: "C. Roads",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Dyes extracted from fruits, flowers, barks and roots are known as",
A: "Colour dyes",
B: "Pigment dyes",
C: "Synthetic dyes",
D: "Vegetable dyes",
answer: "D. Vegetable dyes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Perspective is an optical illusion suggesting",
A: "Balance",
B: "Distance",
C: "Symmetry",
D: "Weight",
answer: "B. Distance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The most basic element in drawing is",
A: "Colour",
B: "Line",
C: "Space",
D: "Texture",
answer: "B. Line",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The difference between pottery and ceramics is that",
A: "Ceramic wares are fired to higher temperatures",
B: "Only ceramic wares are glazed",
C: "Only pottery wares are breakable",
D: "Pottery wares are dried before firing",
answer: "A. Ceramic wares are fired to higher temperatures",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Mirror images are best examples of",
A: "Asymmetrical balance",
B: "Approximate symmetrical",
C: "Symmetrical balance",
D: "Radial balance",
answer: "C. Symmetrical balance",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A small piece of coloured glass, marble or stone used in mosaic is termed",
A: "Stained glass",
B: "Stele",
C: "Stucco",
D: "Tesserae",
answer: "D. Tesserae",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A technique of painting on a plastered surface of a wall is termed",
A: "Buon fresco",
B: "Fresco",
C: "Fresco secco",
D: "Gesso fresco",
answer: "A. Buon fresco",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The open image area for screen printing is called",
A: "Frottage",
B: "Motif",
C: "Stencil",
D: "Template",
answer: "C. Stencil",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Words written under an illustration are termed",
A: "Caption",
B: "Cartoon",
C: "Letterset",
D: "Text",
answer: "A. Caption",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The process of removing unwanted areas of a picture is known as",
A: "Bleeding",
B: "Blowing up",
C: "Cropping",
D: "Trimming",
answer: "C. Cropping",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The value of a colour that is produced after mixing the colour with white is a",
A: "Hatching",
B: "Primary",
C: "Shade",
D: "Tint",
answer: "D. Tint",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Quick sketches are very important in",
A: "Capturing events",
B: "Developing interest in drawing",
C: "Drawing bigger objects",
D: "Understanding the sketches",
answer: "A. Capturing events",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The purpose of an armature in modelling is to",
A: "Give beauty to a work",
B: "Increase the height of a work",
C: "Increase the value of a work",
D: "To give support to the work",
answer: "D. To give support to the work",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following options is an example of primary clay?",
A: "Ball clay",
B: "Fired clay",
C: "Kaolin",
D: "Slip",
answer: "C. Kaolin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Indians painted Buddhist themes on wall in",
A: "Acrylics",
B: "Frescoes",
C: "Oils",
D: "Tempera",
answer: "B. Frescoes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A curator works in the",
A: "Archive",
B: "Library",
C: "Museum",
D: "Studio",
answer: "C. Museum",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The influence of African sculpture on European art resulted in the information of",
A: "Colonialism",
B: "Cubism",
C: "Impressionism",
D: "Surrealism",
answer: "B. Cubism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Chiwara mask is supposed to be an image of a/an",
A: "Antelope",
B: "Donkey",
C: "Leopard",
D: "Lion",
answer: "A. Antelope",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Select from the options an instrument used in measuring temperature in the kiln",
A: "Barometer",
B: "Speedometer",
C: "Pyrometer",
D: "Thermometer",
answer: "C. Pyrometer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]